<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bits &amp; pieces - Sven Wehrend</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bits &amp; pieces - Sven Wehrend</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How does a CPU work 2? Overview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/pages/overview2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/pages/overview2/</guid>
      <description>From Combinatorial to Sequential Logic - Introduction Introduction to Sequential Logic
We get from purely conmbinatorial logic circuits wihout any form of memeory to sequential logic circuits with some type of memory (mostly flipflops)
Clocks,Flipflops and registers Clocks,flipflops and registers
We make a leap into the area of sequential logic and introduce some concepts vital for the sequential logics, like clock, flipflops and registers
Automata Automata
We introduce the two (three) different automata Mealy, Moore (and Medwedjew).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does a CPU work? Overview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/pages/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/pages/overview/</guid>
      <description>Introduction and overview Introduction and overview
Every topic of this course is broken up into two parts: A part about the mathematical side of digital logic, ideally almost independent from implementation details and a more concrete part handling this very details. In the concrete part we will mostly discuss the implementation on an electrical layer, though there are still other solutions possible based on fluid dynamics, or optical gates, most computers and logic gates are still based on electronics and semiconductor technology and this will not change with quantum computing, which is mostly tied to / adjunct to probability theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/pages/about/</guid>
      <description>A simple static blog meant for writing about topics like electronics &amp;amp; computation and - maybe - philosophy.
Dear reader of my humble blog , I am Sven Wehrend, a scanner personality born 1987, interested in a wide range of different topics reaching from technology over psychology to spirituality.
I studied Computer Engineering at the HTW Berlin (Bachelor) and TU Berlin (Master).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prequel: Introduction to electronics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/pages/prequel-short-introduction-to-electronics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/pages/prequel-short-introduction-to-electronics/</guid>
      <description>While I was about to write the implementation part of the boolean algebra post, the basic logic gates, the writing process got quickly out of hand and I caught myself to write more about less connected topics like explaining basic electronic components and their implementation on silicon than the actual content, here shall be the place for those excursions. This is not meant to be a complete reference more a supplement to existing literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prequel: Introduction to electronics - 102</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/pages/short-introduction-to-electronics-102/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/pages/short-introduction-to-electronics-102/</guid>
      <description>After reviewing and extensively describing the most important component, the resistor, in the first part, now we want to have a look at the next important component, the capacitor. Capacitor are also passive components, meaning they do not amplify a signal.
Electrostatic field If we take two metal planes and park them side by side, with a small thin layer of a non-conducting substance in-between, we created an electrostatic field.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
