<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bits &amp; pieces - Sven Wehrend</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bits &amp; pieces - Sven Wehrend</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Compiling Kicad on Debian Bullseye</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/27_compiling_kicad_on_debian_bullseye/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/27_compiling_kicad_on_debian_bullseye/</guid>
      <description>With my new hobby, there came the desire to learn to build and design my own PCB. With that in mind, I began to use the open source ecad solution Kicad. Now I became interested in participating in this project, but, to compile the code you have endure a few challenges - you know, collecting the dependencies,installing them, choose the right branch whiche compiles down and so on. Here I want to show you my experience with that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FPGA 101: Get the Nandland Go board ready on Debian Bullseye</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/26_get_the_nandlab_go_board_ready_on_debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/26_get_the_nandlab_go_board_ready_on_debian/</guid>
      <description>Hi there,
finally this week the nandland go board I ordered from the developer Russell Merrick a month ago arrived. It took a detour due to some shipping problems, but this is not about that, so. I had to face quite a few obstacles to get this running on my Debian Bullseye.
Serial Connection via USB First of all, to connect to the board via FTDI usb as suggested on Debian Bullseye you have to first add your user to the group &amp;#39;dialout&amp;#39;, this is done like below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A favorite hobby of mine: Lustiges Taschenbuch Nr. 162</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/ltb162/25_ltb162/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/ltb162/25_ltb162/</guid>
      <description>It is about time, to share another favorite of mine with you, and this is duckburg and the duck universe. I take the LTB (Lustiges Taschenbuch) Nr. 162 as an example from the golden era of the comic series &amp;#34;Lustiges Taschenbuch&amp;#34;
Der goldene Totempfahl (The golden totem pole) In the story &amp;#34;Der goldene Totempfahl&amp;#34; english the golden totem pole, uncle scrooge is making a movie about his life, the story plays in the county of Dawson, where they are getting lost after a storm, they meet the indianer &amp;#34;großer Elch&amp;#34; english &amp;#34;big moose&amp;#34; and are searching for the gold nuggets big moose saved for uncle scrooge back in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FPGA 101: DE10-nano board: Hello World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/24_fpga_beginners_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/24_fpga_beginners_3/</guid>
      <description>Today I want to show you, how to connect to the DE10-nano board, the successor of the DE0-nano board. It is a bit bigger, costs nearly 300 bucks, but also supports Linux out-of-the-box. There is an Angstrom Linux installed on the SD-card.
To connect to the board via the UART interface, power-up the board with the wall-wart,enter the sd-card to start the linux booting, and finally connect the micro-b usb cable (like shown below) with the PC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FPGA 101: Starting with Quartus and Verilog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/23_fpga_beginners_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/23_fpga_beginners_2/</guid>
      <description>So, you decided you want to learn fpga programming and have done the prerequisite from the introduction 0 as well as done the simple logic circuit via quartus’s bdf files. Today we want to show you how to figure out Quartus by doing another hardware equivalent of the hello-World program used in the software world - we do program a binary counter showing of by the LED array we have available on our DE0-nano board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FPGA 101: Starting with Quartus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/22_fpga_beginners_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/22_fpga_beginners_1/</guid>
      <description>So, you decided you want to learn fpga programming and have done the prerequisite from the last blog post. Today we want to show you how to figure out Quartus by doing a hardware equivalent of the hello-World program used in the software world - we call it AndGate because it is simply that - an and gate feed by to push-buttons as input and a status-LED as output. This way we will make use of the Block Diagram Files (bdf) from Quartus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FPGA 101: Starting with HDLS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/21_fpga_beginners_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/21_fpga_beginners_0/</guid>
      <description>Today I want to start a blog post series about hardware programming. We start with an introduction to hardware programming with the FPGA-board DE0 Nano from former Altera now Intel. You see a picture of the small board below. It seems you can still order this board, but I have not tested.
We will show how to setup the environment, in the first step we will (show how to) download and install quartus on a Debian distribution, and configure the programmer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Rare Earth Dependence: The Quest for Alternative Magnetic Materials</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/20_reducing_rare_earth_elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/20_reducing_rare_earth_elements/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Rare earth elements have long been the backbone of high-tech magnets, with metals like neodymium and dysprosium playing pivotal roles in various industries. However, the scarcity and rising demand for these valuable resources have prompted researchers to seek alternative solutions. In an effort to reduce our reliance on rare earth magnets, scientists are exploring innovative materials and alloy combinations. Among the promising contenders is cerium, an abundant and accessible rare earth element, showing potential to replace or augment neodymium magnets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Secrets of Rare Earth Elements: The Remarkable Case of Neodymium</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/19_rare_earth_elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/19_rare_earth_elements/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Rare earth elements, often shrouded in mystery, play a crucial role in our modern world. From smartphones to electric vehicles, renewable energy technologies, and even defense systems, these elements are the unsung heroes that make our daily lives more sustainable, efficient, and connected. In this article, we’ll delve into the fascinating world of rare earth elements, with a focus on the versatile element, neodymium.
The Rare Earth Elements: An Overview Rare earth elements (REEs) are a group of seventeen chemical elements that occupy the lanthanide series of the periodic table, along with scandium and yttrium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Op-Amps introduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/18_op-amps_introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/18_op-amps_introduction/</guid>
      <description>Today I want to speak about op-amps. These wonderful, but mysterious components, we have heavely often appearing in circuit schematica of analog or analog / digital hybrid circuits. We want to demistify these components.
There are two basic thumb rules when handling ideal op-amp circuit. (Real-world op-amp circuits are a bit more complicated, but we will discuss this later).
1. The first thumb rule is that Vout is essentially the difference of the voltage values at the both inputs, multiplied with an arbitrary but high amplification factor A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analog Computers 101</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/17_analog_computers_101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/17_analog_computers_101/</guid>
      <description>Today I want to speak about analog computers. In todays times analog computers are leading a shadowy existence, compared to their digital counterparts. But they are wonderous little machines. And that machines I mean wordly because there exists analog mechanical computers that are models from the world and used to compute and predict tides in certain areas of the world . Also the brain is an enourmous analog computer with a comparatively very small enery budget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caches and Caching</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/12_caches_and_caching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/12_caches_and_caching/</guid>
      <description>When you fire up your browser to visit a website, you most probably did not noticed a very important mechanism underlying the browser and working in the background. Caching. Caches are used everywhere to optimize and improve access times and such in consequence the overall performance (of a site). Caching in the browser for example means, that ideally only the portions of the website that changed are loaded from the www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topics to write about - Wishlist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/10_wishlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/10_wishlist/</guid>
      <description>This is a small, incomplete list of topics I’d like to write about in the mid- to far future.
Caches
Interrupts
Out-of-Order execution
RAW, WAR and WAW conflicts
Filters (analog and digital)
Analog computers
neuronal networks
the macrobiom</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religion vs. spirituality - why I prefer the latter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/08_religion_spirituality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/08_religion_spirituality/</guid>
      <description>What I have learned about religions and spirituality over the last years and decades boils down to one simple statement: Religion is about right and wrong and old, outdated dogmas, while spirituality simply says &amp;#34;It is how it is&amp;#34;. For spirituality, there is no right or wrong, only the single moment in the present in which we dwell. I find this viewpoint quite amazing. From what I found, it leads to a more awakened state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why are serial interfaces everywhere - instead of parallel ones</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/07_serial_interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/07_serial_interfaces/</guid>
      <description>USB, SPI, I²C, Sata - all these interfaces is common that they are serial interfaces. Serial interfaces are todays common. But why is that the case, especially for high-speed communication? it sounds simply counterintuitive: Parallel wires can theoretically send more bits per time than on singular wire can. The answer to that question is complex and multilayered. There are multiple different reasons why serial interfaces are preferred over parallel interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Odoo hacks: Remove Lock-Button from Odoo v12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/04_odoo_hacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/04_odoo_hacks/</guid>
      <description>Today I want to introduce a solution for a usability-problem I had in Odoo recently. In Odoo 12 there is a lock button next to the edit / save button, and you have to click both to (1) unlock the page and (2) make it editable. This should be done in one step, effectively removing the locking mechanism used in the Delivery Orders (class StockPicking) and Manufacturing Orders (class MrpProduction).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Separating blog and content</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/03_separate_form_and_content/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/03_separate_form_and_content/</guid>
      <description>As the blog grow bigger and after the move to odoo, I noticed a gap in the workflow,since a blog and its content itself are different entities, I wanted to handle them as such, that led me to a cleanup of the original source code for blog, where I moved teh content folder into a different repo, called hugo_content, the former repo I called hugo_blog. ---
In my case, this means you have to clone the repo hugo_blog first go inside the new directory (cd hugo ), checkout its branch &amp;#39;hugo&amp;#39; and then do a clone of the repo hugo_content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to Hugo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/02_moving-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 12:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/02_moving-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Since one week my blog is build on the static-site-generator Hugo. I wanted to move to Hugo far earlier, due to the wide variety of themes. However this required the move from Asciidoc to Asciidoctor, and I experienced a few problems with the integration of Asciidoctor into my existing workflow. As the approach of rendering the latex-equations in the asciidoc-documents no loger worked, I decided to move on to client-based rendering of formulas, like done in KaTex and Mathjax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a static blog with Nikola</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/00_setting_up_nikola/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/00_setting_up_nikola/</guid>
      <description>I picked up Nikola some months ago as I was searching for a simple static-site-generator to setup a blog with minimal effort.
To make things a bit more interesting and at the same time easier we will use Nikola in a Docker container. So I require an almost basic understanding for Docker here.
First create a directory on our host system, where you want the files stored, e.g. &amp;#39;blog&amp;#39; in your home directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing about math with Asciidoc</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/01_writing-about-math-with-asciidoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/01_writing-about-math-with-asciidoc/</guid>
      <description>While drafting a blog post, part of a series of posts intended to be published in the future, I discovered a lack of my tooling in Nikola. When adding mathematical formulas, I realized that there is no default-way of rendering images from those math formulas, and inserting them as image-tags into the html. Instead math formulas are handled via JS, which I try to reduce to an absolute minimum on my site.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
