<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fpga on Bits &amp; pieces - Sven Wehrend</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/fpga/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fpga on Bits &amp; pieces - Sven Wehrend</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/fpga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FPGA 101: Get the Nandland Go board ready on Debian Bullseye</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/26_get_the_nandlab_go_board_ready_on_debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/26_get_the_nandlab_go_board_ready_on_debian/</guid>
      <description>Hi there,
finally this week the nandland go board I ordered from the developer Russell Merrick a month ago arrived. It took a detour due to some shipping problems, but this is not about that, so. I had to face quite a few obstacles to get this running on my Debian Bullseye.
Serial Connection via USB First of all, to connect to the board via FTDI usb as suggested on Debian Bullseye you have to first add your user to the group &amp;#39;dialout&amp;#39;, this is done like below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FPGA 101: DE10-nano board: Hello World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/24_fpga_beginners_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/24_fpga_beginners_3/</guid>
      <description>Today I want to show you, how to connect to the DE10-nano board, the successor of the DE0-nano board. It is a bit bigger, costs nearly 300 bucks, but also supports Linux out-of-the-box. There is an Angstrom Linux installed on the SD-card.
To connect to the board via the UART interface, power-up the board with the wall-wart,enter the sd-card to start the linux booting, and finally connect the micro-b usb cable (like shown below) with the PC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FPGA 101: Starting with Quartus and Verilog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/23_fpga_beginners_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/23_fpga_beginners_2/</guid>
      <description>So, you decided you want to learn fpga programming and have done the prerequisite from the introduction 0 as well as done the simple logic circuit via quartus’s bdf files. Today we want to show you how to figure out Quartus by doing another hardware equivalent of the hello-World program used in the software world - we do program a binary counter showing of by the LED array we have available on our DE0-nano board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FPGA 101: Starting with Quartus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/22_fpga_beginners_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/22_fpga_beginners_1/</guid>
      <description>So, you decided you want to learn fpga programming and have done the prerequisite from the last blog post. Today we want to show you how to figure out Quartus by doing a hardware equivalent of the hello-World program used in the software world - we call it AndGate because it is simply that - an and gate feed by to push-buttons as input and a status-LED as output. This way we will make use of the Block Diagram Files (bdf) from Quartus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FPGA 101: Starting with HDLS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/21_fpga_beginners_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/21_fpga_beginners_0/</guid>
      <description>Today I want to start a blog post series about hardware programming. We start with an introduction to hardware programming with the FPGA-board DE0 Nano from former Altera now Intel. You see a picture of the small board below. It seems you can still order this board, but I have not tested.
We will show how to setup the environment, in the first step we will (show how to) download and install quartus on a Debian distribution, and configure the programmer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
