<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web on Bits &amp; pieces - Sven Wehrend</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web on Bits &amp; pieces - Sven Wehrend</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Caches and Caching</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/12_caches_and_caching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/12_caches_and_caching/</guid>
      <description>When you fire up your browser to visit a website, you most probably did not noticed a very important mechanism underlying the browser and working in the background. Caching. Caches are used everywhere to optimize and improve access times and such in consequence the overall performance (of a site). Caching in the browser for example means, that ideally only the portions of the website that changed are loaded from the www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topics to write about - Wishlist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/10_wishlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/10_wishlist/</guid>
      <description>This is a small, incomplete list of topics I’d like to write about in the mid- to far future.
Caches
Interrupts
Out-of-Order execution
RAW, WAR and WAW conflicts
Filters (analog and digital)
Analog computers
neuronal networks
the macrobiom</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Odoo hacks: Remove Lock-Button from Odoo v12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/04_odoo_hacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/04_odoo_hacks/</guid>
      <description>Today I want to introduce a solution for a usability-problem I had in Odoo recently. In Odoo 12 there is a lock button next to the edit / save button, and you have to click both to (1) unlock the page and (2) make it editable. This should be done in one step, effectively removing the locking mechanism used in the Delivery Orders (class StockPicking) and Manufacturing Orders (class MrpProduction).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Separating blog and content</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/03_separate_form_and_content/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/03_separate_form_and_content/</guid>
      <description>As the blog grow bigger and after the move to odoo, I noticed a gap in the workflow,since a blog and its content itself are different entities, I wanted to handle them as such, that led me to a cleanup of the original source code for blog, where I moved teh content folder into a different repo, called hugo_content, the former repo I called hugo_blog. ---
In my case, this means you have to clone the repo hugo_blog first go inside the new directory (cd hugo ), checkout its branch &amp;#39;hugo&amp;#39; and then do a clone of the repo hugo_content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to Hugo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/02_moving-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 12:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/02_moving-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Since one week my blog is build on the static-site-generator Hugo. I wanted to move to Hugo far earlier, due to the wide variety of themes. However this required the move from Asciidoc to Asciidoctor, and I experienced a few problems with the integration of Asciidoctor into my existing workflow. As the approach of rendering the latex-equations in the asciidoc-documents no loger worked, I decided to move on to client-based rendering of formulas, like done in KaTex and Mathjax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a static blog with Nikola</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/00_setting_up_nikola/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/web/00_setting_up_nikola/</guid>
      <description>I picked up Nikola some months ago as I was searching for a simple static-site-generator to setup a blog with minimal effort.
To make things a bit more interesting and at the same time easier we will use Nikola in a Docker container. So I require an almost basic understanding for Docker here.
First create a directory on our host system, where you want the files stored, e.g. &amp;#39;blog&amp;#39; in your home directory.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
